<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Somtom&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Somtom&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Munich Bike Data Info Graphic</title>
      <link>/post/munich-bike-data-info-graphic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/munich-bike-data-info-graphic/</guid>
      <description>During this year’s summer break there had been a railway construction site which affected the train I usually use for commuting to work. This led to a lot of additional commuting time. Thus, I decided to repair my old mountain bike and give it a try to go to work by bike.
During the one hour ride I wondered how many people made the same decision and if there would be any data about Munich bike traffic with the use of which I could get some insights about Munich’s bike traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USA School Shootings</title>
      <link>/post/usa-school-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/usa-school-shootings/</guid>
      <description>22…… this is the count of school shootings which took place in USA within the first 21 weeks in 2018. Statistically this means that there has been more than 1 shooting per week. The Washington Post wrote that this led to more deaths at schools than members of the US military have been killed while being deployed this year.
We hear about those shootings quite often in the news, and after almost every of theses a new discussion about the USA gun laws arises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco Crime Heatmaps in R Using BigQuery bigrquery and ggmap</title>
      <link>/post/san-francisco-crime-heatmaps-in-r-using-bigquery-bigrquery-and-ggmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/san-francisco-crime-heatmaps-in-r-using-bigquery-bigrquery-and-ggmap/</guid>
      <description>The aim of today’s blog post is to give a short introduction into the usage of BigQuery inside of R. BigQuery is a product within the Google Cloud Platform and serves as a data warehouse for storage and analytics at high scale. It supports standard SQL dialect which makes it easy to use for people with SQL experience.
We are going to use one of the public data sets available on BigQuery and have a short look at the recorded incidents of the San Francisco Police Departments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oktoberfest Analysis Part II</title>
      <link>/post/oktoberfest-analysis-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/oktoberfest-analysis-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Everybody knows the Oktoberfest which takes place in Munich every year. In this blog post series we are going to look into a public availabe dataset and try to gain some insights about the Oktoberfest.
In the first part we loaded and described the data. We also analysed the price and consumption of beer and hendl (chicken) over the years.
In this second part we are going to have a closer look at the Bavarian Central Agricultural Festival - also known as “ZLF”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oktoberfest Analysis Part I</title>
      <link>/post/oktoberfest-analysis-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/oktoberfest-analysis-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Everybody knows the Oktoberfest which takes place in Munich every year. In this blog post series we are going to look into a public available data set and try to gain some insights about the Oktoberfest.
In the first part we load and describe the data. Furthermore, we will analyse the price and consumption of beer and hendl (chicken) over the years.
In the second part we are going to have a closer look at the Bavarian Central Agricultural Festival - also known as “ZLF” - and its influence on beer- and hendl consumption, as well as on visitor count.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>